<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="main.xsl" ?>
<title>Gregg Shorthand</title>
<paragraph>&#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;Gregg Shorthand&#8212;named 
              after its inventor, John Robert Gregg&#8212;is a system of pen stenography 
              that gained popularity in the United States in the early twentieth 
              century. &nbsp;However, since the invention of mechanical stenography 
              and the oversimplification of the Gregg Shorthand system in its 
              <em>Series 90</em> version, the form lost its appeal to the public. 
              &#xA0;Only twenty years ago, shorthand classes were seen in nearly 
              every high school in the country. &nbsp;Now, the overwhelming majority 
              of high school students today has never seen nor heard of Gregg 
              Shorthand.<br />
              &#xA0; &#xA0; &#xA0;The purpose of this site is to increase awareness 
              of Gregg Shorthand, and refresh those who learned it and have not 
              used it in several years. &nbsp;However, the year in which one learned 
              it in school affects how he or she writes. &nbsp;As vocabulary and 
              needs change, so does the version of Gregg Shorthand.<br />
              &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;The current system&#8212;according to the owners 
              of the former Gregg Publishing Company, McGraw-Hill&#8212;is the 
              Centennial Version. &nbsp;This version is good for business dictation, 
              having more brief forms than its predecessors, the <em>Series 90</em> 
              and <em>Diamond Jubilee</em> series. Most experts find, though, 
              that for serious court reporting and stenography, the 1949 <em>Simplified</em> 
              and, even better, the 1929 <em>Anniversary</em> Series is most efficient. 
              &nbsp;The series for a person now is dependent on why he or she 
              needs shorthand. &nbsp;If he or she has good interest, determination, 
              and time, <em>Anniversary</em> or <em>Simplified</em> is recommended. 
              &nbsp;If one merely wants to know shorthand to take notes faster 
              without much time studying the system, he or she may use one of 
              the later systems.<br />
              <em>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;<a href="indexgrga.shtml">An Anniversary 
              Gregg version of this body text</a></em><br />
              &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;<em><a href="indexgrg.shtml">A Simplified Gregg 
              version of this body text</a></em></paragraph>